Yampiero A. Polanco

Software Engineer

New York, NY 1003-347.533.1595 Email - LinkedIn - GitHub - jppolanco.dev

Summary: The journey has been long but rewarding, and I have gained knowledge from many different spaces and industries. From data management and sales, database design and implementation, to financial technology support, my journey thus far has been an extensive one. These experiences inspired me to attend General Assembly where I gained the skills and experience to become a full stack software engineer. Throughout all of this, one thing remains true- my love for technology continues to grow. My desire to solve problems in the world with technology increases every day. Today I continue to impact the lives around me and solve problems, with the same tool that inspired me while young, technology!

SKILLS

Technical: HTM, CSS, JavaScript, React, PostgreSQL. Express, Sequelize, API, JSON, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Active Admin, Axios, Bcrypt, Surge, Heroku, DOM manipulation, Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

Business: Team Management, Data Analytics

EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY/ New York, NY

Software Engineering Fellow

March 2020 - June 2020

- Designed a full stack networking web application, using react fronting and Ruby on Rails backend.
- Developed a React application that serves as recipe database using a third- party API through AXIOS
- Lead a team developers/engineers to build an interactive outfit creation web application with CRUD functionality, using React frontend and PostgresSQL backend with Sequelize and Express.

BLOOMBERG LP / New York, NY

March 2018 - March 2020

Financial Product Analyst/Sales- Account Manager/EMSX Trading/Equity Specialist

- Built and managed Managed relationships between 900 North East users and Bloomberg, with a sales goal of 1.2M in ancillary products.
- Implemented and trained 80% of my user base on new techniques and trading strategies increasing platform usage.
- Increase firm dependency on the Bloomberg Platform, by displacing competitors in the same space. Helped save clients about a 1M in ancillary products.
- Handled 98.8% new product implementation across Bloomberg's 300K+ global users.
- Report bugs and UX/UI fixes and changes to our engineering team, while acting as a communication bridge between clients and engineering.
- Resolve upwards of 100 daily client inquiries on Bloomberg's Terminal system and functionality.

GETTING OUT AND STAYING OUT INC / New York, NY

August 2016 - February 2018

Chief Technology Officer/ Director of Measurements and Outcomes/ Contract Manager

- Collect, analyze and present client outcomes to Board of Directors, Foundations and government agencies.
- Designed and implemented Sales Force database to manage a growing client base.
- Developed a new financial strategy that increased company efficiency, which reduced cost while ensuring that risks were remediated and addressed.
- Lead on the implementation of new Case Management Software. Lead on a global team that migrated over 6,000 client cases from old platform to new platform.
- Manage \$2,500,000 in Government grants and incentives.

EXIT REALTY / New York, NY

March 2014 - August 2016

Real Estate Sales Person/Senior Data Analyst

- Develop data backed research for investors utilizing data mining techniques, which include ROI, projections, demographics, occupancy planning and rent value. This information is adaptable to both commercial and residential real estate.
- Listing agent for properties valued at approximately 500K, generating 1.5M in my first year.
- Taught and assisted other agents on the best practices of Real Estate, including how to generate leads and close more business.

AWARDS /LEADERSHIP

Bloomberg Asset Class Customer Service Award, 5000 hr New York City Award, StreetWise Partner- Mentor

EDUCATION

General Assembly, New York, NY
University at Albany, Albany NY,
Bachelon

Program: Software Engineering Immersive **Bachelors of Arts:** Information Science